Yomogi Kindergarten
There.
Oh... That one's damaged too, is it?
I hope we could purchase new ones.
If we fix them, they can still be used.
Besides, new isn't everything.
How are your university studies going?
How? Ah, the same as always.
Are you going to classes?
Are you getting your credits?
Of course.
That's good.
I was concerned because
you're always working.
Good morning, Kobato!
Good Mor...
There she goes again! Kobato fell!
You're all covered in dirt!
Are you all right, Kobato?
Give me a break.
Who trips where there's nothing to trip over?
Ow...
Oh uh, thank you.
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...Gentle Person.
Fujimoto.
Let me help you. Please. I'd like to!
Whatever.
Yes!
Um... Fujimoto?
There's something I've been wanting to ask you!
Fujimoto?
Be quiet and move your hands.
Seeing that you have plenty
of time to open your mouth.
Okay.
What is it?
Yes?
What is it you've been wanting to ask me?
Oh? Ah, yes...
Well...
It's about that strange phone call the other day.
Why am I not to tell Ms. Sayaka about it?
Just because.
Why "just because"?
If you can't keep it a secret, stop coming here.
If you tell her, you'll upset her. That's why.
Upset? Ms. Sayaka?
Do you want to help? Or do you
just want to get in my way?
What's the matter, Kobato?
Fujimoto's mad at me again.
Did he scold you?
Yes. Because I keep getting in his
way when he's trying to work.
I think you should apologize, then.
We'll go and apologize with you.
No!
They have just been painted so do not touch!
I think he gets angry because
he worries about you.
Do you think so?
Of course, Kobato. Lighten up.
My mom tells me she scolds me because
she expects me to be a good kid.
You're right. I'll apologize and
ask him to let me help again.
Huh?
He's not here.
I wonder what this is.
Huh? That's probably Fujimoto's essay.
Essay?
I think he's going to need this today.
Kobato, would you please take this to him?
You want me to go?
He'd probably be in trouble without it.
Then I will take it to him!
What's up? You're awfully upbeat.
I need to have him acknowledge that
I don't always get in the way.
That I can be helpful at times.
The place called "university" that
Fujimoto goes to is this way, isn't it?
I hope you got directions on how to get there!
Yes. But what is "university"?
You mean you came all this way
without even knowing that?!
Not that your ignorance surprises me anymore.
A university is a place where
people study difficult things.
They study?
Yeah. Like you know, if there's something you
want to do, or a career you want to pursue.
Something you want to do...
All these people. Look at all the people!
Well it is a university after all.
It's to be expected.
How many Yomogi Kindergartens
could fit in here, do you think?
Why are you comparing?!
Just hurry up and find him!
Yes sir, Ioryogi-san!
Um...
U-Um, sorry!
Um... well... huh?
Stop getting lost!
He's nowhere around. Fujimoto.
But all we're doing is
roaming around the campus!
Kobato is ready!
It's Fujimoto!
What are you waiting for?
Yes of course, I have to get this to him!
Hey, hey! Don't trip again!
Sorry. Are you all right?
Yes.
Oh!
No, it was my fault. Sorry.
No worries, I'm okay.
That's a cute little doll you have. Here you go.
Thank you very much.
Oh, and this... Are you a friend of Fujimoto?
No!
Well, I mean, I'm not his friend, but um...
Kind of like a friend?
Ah, yes. Maybe.
Me too.
Huh? And you are?
Oh. I'm Takashi Domoto. And you?
H-How do you do?! I'm Kobato Hanato!
I came here to deliver Fujimoto
something he forgot.
Fujimoto!
I was sure he was around here somewhere.
He ran off.
What?
Actually, I said something that upset him.
Again?
"Again"?
Fujimoto always gets mad!
Oh, but, but!
That's because I'm always messing up.
But still! I think he gets mad too often!
Oh, but no... I'm always the one at
fault. He's done nothing wrong.
I see.
So you're from Yomogi Kindergarten.
Yes! I help there!
Gotcha! Why don't we look for
Fujimoto together, Kobato.
You sure? Are you sure you don't mind?
Would I be getting in your way?
Oh no, of course not! I'd appreciate that!
Great!
Right now... he's probably in Philosophy of Law.
Don't worry, I'm sure he's
at school all day today.
I don't think he can afford
the time to work much.
Is that right?
It's almost exam time.
Fujimoto always looks busy.
You're right.
In his case, he'd have an easy time
with any seminar he wanted,
but he chooses to make work his priority.
Well, that's what makes him Fujimoto.
Hey Domoto!
Do me a favor!
What is it?
We need your help!
It's the paper for Professor Hayakawa.
We don't know where to begin!
How can he expect us to
have it in by next week?
All right, all right. I'll help you.
Yay!
Thanks, Domoto.
You do understand that I'm just going to
help you. You've got to do the work.
We know!
Anyway, thanks!
Oh, well.
Let's go.
Fujimoto? Haven't seen him.
Did you try the library?
Thanks.
If you see him, could you let him
know I'm looking for him?
What?!
No way!
The guy's unfriendly. He intimidates me.
He's not like that.
No, really, I can't. Sorry.
H-Hey...
Is everyone afraid of Fujimoto?
Huh?
Well, you know. He isn't the outgoing type. And
he always looks like he's angry at something.
To you, too?
Well you said that you'd made him angry.
Fujimoto had reason to get mad.
He's always been the type not
to need help from anybody.
But I opened my big mouth and kind of
gave him advice about his future.
I've been aware of his personality for a very long
time. I should've just kept my mouth shut.
Why is that?
Well, I just can't turn my back on the guy.
Ms. Sayaka!
What is it?
We're all waiting for you!
Come on, let's play!
Oh I'm sorry. You're bored because
Fujimoto and Kobato aren't here today.
N-No, it's not that!
Wait just a little bit longer, okay?
Ms. Sayaka!
Someone's here to see you!
Hello!
It's Chiho and Chise!
Chitose?
What's the matter?
Guess what?
Mommy and Chiho and I
made some macaroons!
So we brought them for you to try!
Right?
Oh my...
Thank you!
These are good!
Light and crispy!
Sayaka.
Where are Fujimoto and Kobato?
They're at the university today.
Kobato too?
Fujimoto? I just saw him leave.
I see. Thanks. We'll look elsewhere then.
Hey Domoto!
You get along well with
Professor Tomita, don't you?
Could you put in a word for me?
I can't afford to drop this credit.
Have you told him yourself?
Naw, it's kind of awkward you know?
He values your opinion.
If you could just break the ice with one word...
All right, I'll mention you.
For real?! Thanks, I owe you one!
But you've got to go and talk
to him yourself afterwards.
I know that. Thanks, I appreciate it!
Everyone relies on Domoto
don't they, Ioryogi-san?
I know that. Thanks, I appreciate it!
Everyone relies on Domoto
don't they, Ioryogi-san?
Kobato.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Not at all.
Do you mind if we stop by somewhere?
Oh, okay...
I know you mean well, but he's
missed too many classes.
And he feels very bad about it.
Please, Professor. Could you
possibly overlook that part?
I understand. If you really insist.
Thank you, sir.
Sorry to keep you.
Domoto, you're amazing.
Amazing? Why?
So many people rely on you
and you help everybody out.
You think so?
Yes!
I really want to help others out, but I can't
do that well. I respect you, Domoto.
Thank you... I guess...
Huh?
Oh, no, nothing. Shall we go?
Ah, yes!
One, two, three!
Oh no, I lost!
Well then Chiho, you're it. Everyone, let's hide!
One! Two!
I see. So she went to the university.
She was quite excited about taking it to him.
That sounds like Kobato.
Oh. Sayaka, I want you to look at these.
Yukari?
Chise?
Wh-Which are you?
Gotcha, Yukari!
Ch-Chiho, it was you?!
This person says he might be
able to help you with a loan.
This is an accountant friend of mine.
And this person...
I'm sorry Chitose.
Sayaka, do you understand?
I'm not trying to help you
because I feel sorry for you.
It's because I want to protect the kindergarten
that my children and I all graduated from.
So no more apologizing, okay?
Right. Thanks.
There he is, finally.
What do you mean?!
You were just skipping class. I have no desire to
help anyone out who would do such a thing.
What the heck?! If you don't want
to help me out, just say so!
All right. I don't want to. I refuse.
Forget it!
Darn! I should never have asked
that jerk in the first place!
What are you doing here?
Fujimoto, you're mean!
Why do you say that?
You didn't have to talk mean to her like that!
You purposely made her mad at you!
Otherwise they'll come back for more.
Those people might have
had a very good reason!
None of my business.
They ought to fend for themselves.
You forgot this! Now it's delivered!
Kobato...
I shouldn't have spoken to him like that.
Kobato.
Domoto...
You were so kind to help me find Fujimoto,
but I ran off without even thanking you.
Um, I'm sorry.
Relax. Have a seat.
Kobato, how long have you known Fujimoto?
Um, since this spring.
I see.
Why do you ask?
I guess I just felt envious.
Huh?
You know. You and Fujimoto.
Me... and Fujimoto?
I've known him longer than you have,
but I can't talk to him like you do.
Yes, I'm sure Fujimoto
feels terrible after that.
I was really rude to him.
No, that's not what I mean.
What you said was correct.
But I can't even tell him what I think is right.
Sorry, I'm just wishing for
what I don't have, I guess.
You have a lot of wonderful features.
You're very kind, for one...
I'm not at all kind.
What? But people come and ask you for your
help. And you help them out. You're very kind.
Well that...
It's simply because I have trouble saying "no".
If I'm really thinking for the good of that person,
I should be refusing, like Fujimoto does.
You were just skipping class. I have no desire to
help anyone out who would do such a thing.
Fujimoto isn't afraid of making
enemies. He's strong.
People probably avoid him because
they're intimidated by that strength.
I envy him... for that strength of his.
Envy him for his strength?
Yeah.
I don't know about Fujimoto, but having
people afraid of you is a lonely thing.
Being disliked is painful.
All those people I met today. The moment they
found out that you'd help, they looked so happy.
But that's...
Domoto.
Is not wanting to be disliked a bad thing?
Is it bad to want to be liked?
Is it bad to try to help people?
Is wanting to do something for someone
who is in trouble a bad thing?
I don't know how to say this well,
but you are a good person.
Thank you.
You're an unusual girl.
Huh? D-Did I say something strange?
Ioryogi-san always gets upset with me,
saying I don't know anything!
Ioryogi-san?
Yes! Ioryogi-san is a stuffed
toy animal, but he talks!
He talks, but I'm not to speak to him!
Hey!
Is Ioryogi-san that doll?
Yes!
Domoto!
Oh. The girls from earlier.
I'd better go, then.
Yes! Thank you very much!
No, thank you. See you.
Yes!
What?!
Why is there another kompeito?!
Because you acknowledged the
kindness of that good-looking guy.
The good-looking guy?
Are you talking about Domoto?
Who else?!
But, but, does just
acknowledging deserve a kompeito?
Regardless of what others think,
some people are very self-conscious.
Is that right?
Yeah, just tells you good-looking guys
have good-looking guys' problems.
By the way, Dobato. About this afternoon.
Yes?
What was the big idea telling that guy about me!
But, but! I didn't speak to you, just as you said!
The moment you tell people about stuffed
toys that talk and talking to stuffed toys,
you've already gone overboard!
I'm sorry!
Kobato!
30 points!
What?!
No way!
Huh?
I said you were a big help.
That's the same old Fujimoto.
Huh? Huh?
He's pathetic. That guy. In his own way,
he's thanking you the best he knows how.
Thanking me?
Kobato, Teacher Fujimoto isn't
mad at you anymore, is he?
He isn't scary, either. He's a gentle person.
Huh?
He's gentle and kind. He found my house
key for me once when I lost it!
He made a bamboo dragonfly for me once.
Oh, he once gave me a cicada shell.
That's right, and remember that snake slough?
He's not a bad guy.
Right?!
He's an unusual person, Fujimoto.
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...A Kitten's Lullaby.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...A Kitten's Lullaby.